Edward-san!
Thank goodness!
You're coming around, right?
Where am I?
Al!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Sorry about that.
I'll get you back to normal right away, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Edward-san, what in the world
happened at the 5th Laboratory?
Nothing much.
Nothing much? And you were this seriously injured?
It's no big deal.
Jeez, and I was just one step away from getting my hand on the truth, too.
Well, next time, I won't botch things—
Edward-san!
I apologize in advance
for my discourtesy.
You nearly lost your life!
You should recognize that you are still a child!
You could trust us adults
a little more, couldn't you?
My conduct was unbecoming of an inferior officer!
I beg your forgiveness!
No, I'm the one
who's sorry to you.
This is one of Ed's parts, all right.
As someone who's been sung of as
a young, beautiful, gifted Automail engineer,
this is a terrible blunder for me!
Is something the matter?
Ah, no!
N-Nothing at all, nothing at all, really!
Yes, Rockbell Prosthetic-Limb Outfitters.
Winry?
E-Ed?
As it turns out, I can't move my right arm anymore.
Sure enough...
Sure enough?
Ah, you see?
Didn't I tell you that I made it lighter,
so it wouldn't be quite so strong this time?
Jeez, you've gone and done something reckless again, haven't you?
A-Anyhow, I can't get down there right now, so I'm in a fix.
In that case, I'll make the trip!
I'll dash on over, just wait there.
Aren't you unusually kind today?
Oh, I'm always kind!
Okay then, if you would. Thanks.
This time, make sure you do his maintenance right.
Right...
Yo, Ed!
I heard you could get up.
Lieutenant Colonel!
Al, are you okay too?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, that's right.
Would you guys go buy some lunch for me?
Ah, I'll get that myself.
Lieutenant Ross, you go with him.
Understood.
Sorry, I'm just so hungry.
About the 5th Laboratory...
Everything that happened
concerning the incident there
is being chalked up as the doing of Scar,
who was pursuing you.
Of course,
I'm not convinced of that.
There were a lot of bodies left there
that are thought to have been Chimeras.
And a great deal of equipment that I can't help but believe was still operational until just yesterday.
Among the prisoners who were
forcibly taken there by someone,
there are those who said they saw Brig. Gen. Basque Grand, who was killed in the line of duty.
What the hell happened there?
Ed!
How am I supposed to know?
Just tell me what you saw.
Homunculi.
Homunculi?!
You can't be serious!
Still...
they definitely weren't human.
They're tied in with the
Philosopher's Stone, huh?
They were trying to make me create a Philosopher's Stone.
And by using live prisoners, at that.
What the hell...
Isn't that right, Al?
Mm-hmm.
A guardian who was only a spirit...
A dangerous guy named Envy or something...
Not to mention Philosopher's Stone transmutation circles and Uroboros tattoos...
I saw all of them there.
For experiments about a lousy stone,
none of those are laughing matters, huh?
I heard from Marcoh-san
that Philosopher's Stones were used in the Eastern Rebellion.
They said that for some reason,
I was being kept alive
for their sakes.
Thanks for telling me.
Let me handle it from here.
Get some rest.
Right now, you should just think about yourselves.
I'm finally here.
Let's see...
He said he was going to have a sign or something ready for me...
Well, well, if it isn't Winry!
Thank you for taking
the trouble to come so far!
There it is.
No way... I hadn't heard
that you were in a hospital!
Yeah, well, one thing led to another...
It's nothing to laugh about.
Winry?
I didn't maintain you properly,
and now, this has happened.
This isn't particularly your fault!
Right, Al?
Mm-hmm.
There, you hear that?
But...
Your maintenance was perfect!
Besides, sometimes it just happens to stop moving.
If the timing had been different,
what happened might've been worse.
And the reason it broke was because
I was using it too roughly in the first place.
Could it be that he hasn't noticed
that I forgot to tighten that screw?
Well, sure!
Ed, you're always too rough!
Hey...
Excuse me. Lt.
Colonel,
there's a phone call from Colonel Mustang.
Yo! You called at a good time!
I have great news!
You found Scar?!
Huh?! How would that be great news?!
Have you forgotten?
Tomorrow is Elicia-chan's birthday!
Unless you want to turn into charcoal, report your current situation immediately!
Not to worry.
If anything happens, I'll contact you.
More importantly, be sure to send Elicia-chan a present.
Bye now!
Um, are you sure it's okay not to report anything?
It's okay.
Right now, he doesn't
need to know anything.
Never mind that, how are
those reports I requested?
Working without rest,
I've finally finished them!
Okay, here's what's next.
How are you doing, Ed?
What do you know,
you're done eating already.
Y-Yeah.
Well then,
let me fix you right away...
You left your milk.
Ed...
Please, anything but that.
What are you talking about?!
Milk is good for the body! Drink it right now!
Shut up!
If I hate it, I hate it!
Not drinking my milk isn't
particularly going to kill me!
Ah, jeez!
This is the reason why you're always going to be such a bean sprout!
Bean sprout?
That's right, bean sprout.
Right, Al?
That's right, Brother.
You have to drink it.
Yeah, yeah. Good for you, Al.
You got all big without
having to drink this stuff.
I...
didn't get this body
because I wanted to.
S-Sorry...
What's the matter between you two?
Al?
Did something happen?
Well?
Why?
How come you never talk to me?
About your injuries,
or about the two of you?
Here I am, worried sick,
and you won't talk to me
about anything important?!
Ed! Al!
I don't care anymore!
Yo!
Nice to meet you, Winry-chan.
I'm Lt. Col. Maes Hughes.
It's a pleasure.
And this...
is my adorable Elicia-chan!
How about it? Cute, right?
You'd like to meet her, right?
Y-Yeah, sure...
All right!
I'll let you meet her!
Okay then, I'll look after Winry-chan!
Later!
U-Um...
You are so lucky!
After all, tomorrow is
Elicia-chan's birthday.
Now that you mention it, so is Ed's...
Sure.
We'll have to get
a present for him too.
So, what kind of present
are you going to give Elicia-chan?
Huh?
What? A stuffed teddy bear?
And a giant-size one, at that?
Elicia-chan will be thrilled with that!
Happy birthday, Elicia-chan!
Congratulations!
Way to go, Elicia-chan!
You see, apples are best
if you coat them with syrup.
So that's how you did it.
Lately, my own daughter has been...
Nice, Elicia-chan.
What a cute bear.
Elicia-chan...
Happy birthday.
Here's your present.
Thanks, Miss Bookworm.
Bookworm?
Miss?
Elicia-chan, can you tell me how old you are now?
Four!
How adorable!
Miss, know what?
Congratulations!
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Know what?
Papa says the more people say "congratulations" to you,
the more good things
will happen to you.
That's why I'm telling you too, Miss.
Elicia-chan...
You two almost look
like you're siblings.
Really. I wish I had
a little sister like this.
I'm an only child, after all.
You do have brothers, you know.
Brothers would talk to me
more about things.
For a long time now, they've never talked about anything important with me.
Can't help that.
Guys are creatures that demonstrate things more by their actions than with their words.
As much as possible, they don't want to burden anyone with their adversities.
Nor do they want to worry others.
That's why they bottle everything up.
And even so, when those two
finally do give in and complain,
I'll bet you're the
only one they do it to.
When that happens,
you're the one who receives them.
Isn't that enough?
If their older sister
makes that kind of face,
the younger brothers won't ever
come to depend on her, will they?
Hughes-san...
Here...
Thanks for waiting. I've finished
baking a birthday cake for Ed-kun.
Go ahead, go, go!
Here.
But, Hughes-san, don't you have a present for Ed?
What are you talking about?
There's no present that's a match for your smiling face, Winry-chan.
Congratulations!
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Know what?
They say that on your birthday,
the more you get told "congratulations," the happier you'll be.
Here. This is from Gracia-san.
O-Oh...
I made sure to learn
how to make it from her,
so once you're able to eat,
I can make it for you at any time, Al.
Mm-hmm.
Now that you mention it,
when we were kids,
the three of us always
used to eat cake together, huh?
Uh-huh. And that one time, Den ate Al's cake.
And then Al bawled.
Right, right.
I-Is that so?
You were still little.
Don't you remember?
Mm-mm.
Is something the matter?
I'll be outside until you
finish repairing Brother.
Al...
Are you sure
you're okay out here?
Yes.
Okay, I'll come back
to get you later.
Thanks.
Say, Ed,
something happened
between you and Al, huh?
I...
did something awful to him.
I had the chance to
return him back to normal,
but I hesitated.
How come?
I would have had to
sacrifice other people.
In comparison with Al,
they should have been people who I didn't care about...
But I couldn't do it...
while he watched from the sidelines...
It's good that you didn't.
After all, Al wouldn't be happy
if someone else
ended up being sacrificed,
even if it did mean
he could return to normal.
But still...
More importantly,
I wonder if Al isn't upset
over seeing you about to sacrifice someone even once, Ed.
Suppose your personality and memories
were implanted in you
as it suited your brother.
These people are all homunculi—
perfectly created humans.
Was I ever really human?
All finished.
Come on, let's go see Al.
But...
what do I say to him?
What are you talking about?
Just say "sorry"
and apologize to him.
You're always stuck for words.
All right.
Al...
I'm sorry.
I'll fix you up right away.
Look, I brought a bunch of stuff from Resembool.
Al, I'm not giving up.
We'll do things our way
and get ourselves back to normal for sure, okay?
No matter what.
Maybe you can get back to normal like that, Brother,
but I wonder if the same goes for me.
Of course it does. Don't sweat it.
Here goes.
How's that?
That's the way you bonded my soul to this armor back then, huh?
Yeah.
Along with my memories...
Memories are nothing more than simply information, after all.
An alchemist as good as you, Brother,
would have no trouble concocting a person's memories, right?
Is that...
what you've been ruminating about?
Brother...
Earlier in Resembool, there was something you were about to tell me, remember?
Something you were too afraid to say to me till now.
It was that my soul and
memories and everything
are really something fake that you came up with, wasn't it?
No! What Ed wanted
to say to you was—
Never mind!
After all, the person named Alphonse Elric
never existed in this world.
What are you saying?!
You two have always been together!
Besides, there's been me
and Grandma!
Believe me, Al!
What would you have me believe?
What would you have me believe, with this hollow body?
It's possible that all of you are deceiving me together, isn't it?
You've...
been keeping that
to yourself all this time?
Is that all you have to say?
What about you, Brother?! Answer my question!
Why don't you say anything?!
Why?!
Let go of me.
There's no point in me living!
You stupid jerk!
Let go of me! Let go of me!
Al!
Let go of me!
Ed!
Al...
Stay back.
Stay back...
Keep away!
Al!
Ed!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 24: "Bonding Memories"
Even if everybody else has forgotten,
I still remember...
your voice...
your warmth...
your smile...